p53 tumor suppressor your body's cells
p53肿瘤抑制因子 身体细胞的守护者
and tissues are under constant stress
组织持续承受压力。
from the environment such as DNA damage
来自环境的因素，如DNA损伤
from UV light emitted from the Sun
来自太阳发出的紫外线
damage to your DNA causes cells to
损害你的DNA会导致细胞
follow one of three outcomes either the
遵循以下三种结果之一：
cell dies stopped growing permanently or
细胞死亡，停止永久生长。
slows down to repair before resuming
在恢复前减速进行修复
normal growth the protein p53 plays an
正常生长中，蛋白质p53发挥着作用。
essential role in determining this fate
在决定这一命运中起关键作用
p53 plays a critical role in keeping
p53在维持细胞稳态中起着关键作用
cells healthy on our bodies cancer free
我们身体上的细胞健康无癌。
half of all human cancers of p53
人类癌症中半数与p53相关
switched off p53 is found in the nucleus
在细胞核中发现了关闭的p53
of each cell responding to DNA damage
每个细胞对DNA损伤的响应
p53 activates distinct sets of genes
p53激活不同的基因组合
that drive processes such as cell death
驱动细胞死亡等过程
DNA repair or growth arrest and this is
DNA修复或生长停滞，这就是
what determines the outcome of the cell
什么决定了细胞的命运
the activation of genes involved in DNA
DNA相关基因的激活
repair has been linked to p53 x' ability
修复与p53的能力相关联
to suppress cancer in the nucleus DNA is
抑制细胞核内DNA的癌症
wound around histone proteins to create
缠绕在组蛋白上形成
chromatin
染色质
genes are encoded in your DNA p53
基因编码于你的DNA p53中。
targets specific genes controlling
针对控制特定基因的目标
whether they are turned on or off via
无论它们是开启还是关闭
their DNA promoter the DNA promoter
它们的DNA启动子
contains a part specific for p53 known
包含一个针对p53的特异性部分
as the p53 response element the stars of
作为p53反应元件的明星
the gene is found within the core
该基因位于核心区域内。
promoter p53 binds its response elements
启动子p53结合其响应元件
and helps bring RNA polymerase to the
并有助于将RNA聚合酶引导至
start of the gene
基因起始
RNA polymerase is the enzyme responsible
RNA聚合酶是负责转录的酶。
for reading and transcribing for gene
用于基因的读取和转录
code this p53 target gene is currently
编码此p53靶基因目前
off RNA polymerase is not reading the
关闭RNA聚合酶未在读取
gene code the amount of p53 increases in
基因编码的p53数量增加
response to UV induced damage from the
对紫外线引起的损伤的响应
Sun
太阳
[Applause]
[掌声]
the highly dynamic p53 protein is made
高度动态的p53蛋白被合成
of four identical parts each part
四个相同部分中的每个部分
contains a DNA binding domain p53 binds
包含一个DNA结合域，p53蛋白结合于此。
DNA all four DNA binding domains combine
DNA所有四个DNA结合域结合
the response elements in the promoter of
启动子中的反应元件
target genes
靶基因
to turn the gene on p53 does two things
开启p53基因会产生两种作用。
first p53 makes the gene more accessible
首先，p53使基因更易于表达。
by recruiting proteins that remodel the
通过招募重塑蛋白质的
DNA
脱氧核糖核酸
second p53 brings RNA polymerase to the
第二个p53将RNA聚合酶带到
now accessible target gene now switched
目标基因现已激活可及
on the gene will be read and transcribed
基因将被读取并转录。
by RNA polymerase activating pathways
通过RNA聚合酶激活途径
such as soda growth arrest or DNA repair
例如苏打水生长停滞或DNA修复